A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller, Vice Presidential records, New York Office, Series 10 FA380
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Vice Presidential Confirmation Hearings, 1974; 1; 24 Box(es)
  - Senate Rules Committee -Transcripts of Proceedings, Thursday, September 26, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 303)
  - Senate Rules Committee -Transcripts of Proceedings, Thursday, September 26, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 304)
  - Senate Rules Committee -Transcripts of Proceedings, Thursday, September 26, 1974 - John E. Lockwood (JEL) Copy (Box 22, Folder 305)
  - Senate Rules Committee -Transcripts of Proceedings, Thursday, September 26, 1974 - John E. Lockwood (JEL) Copy (Box 22, Folder 306)
  - Senate Rules Committee -Transcripts of Proceedings, November 13, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 307)
  - Senate Rules Committee -Transcripts of Proceedings, November 14, 1974 - Joseph W. Ernst (JWE) Copy (Box 22, Folder 308)
  - Senate Rules Committee -Transcripts of Proceedings, November 14, 1974 - Joseph W. Ernst (JWE) Copy (Box 22, Folder 309)
  - Senate Rules Committee -Transcripts of Proceedings, November 15, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 310)
  - Senate Rules Committee -Transcripts of Proceedings, November 15, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 311)
  - Senate Rules Committee -Transcripts of Proceedings, November 16, 1974; PM Session - Joseph W. Ernst (JWE) Copy (Box 23, Folder 312)
  - Senate Rules Committee -Transcripts of Proceedings, November 17, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 313)
  - Senate Rules Committee -Transcripts of Proceedings, November 17, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 314)
  - Statements - Dilworth, J. Richardson, before the House, December 3, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 315)
    Transcripts of testimony of various individuals before the House and Senate Committees.
  - Statements - Rockefeller, Laurance S., before the House, December 4, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 316)
  - Statements - Rockefeller, Laurance S., before the Senate, November 14, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 317)
  - Statements - Rockefeller, Nelson A., before the House, November 21, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 318)
  - Statements - Rockefeller, Nelson A., before the House, November 21, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 319)
  - NOT USED (Box 24, Folder 320)
  - Statements - Rockefeller, Nelson A., before the Senate, September 23, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 321)
  - Statements - Rockefeller, Nelson A., before the Senate, November 13, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 322)
  - Statements - Witnesses for and against the nomination, before the Senate, September 1974 (Box 24, Folder 323)
  - Telecopied to Washington (Box 24, Folder 324)
    Information, documents, and clippings "telecopied" from the Rockefeller family offices in New York to NAR's staff in Washington for use in the hearings.
  - Triborough Bridge and Tunnel Authority (Box 24, Folder 325)
  - Video Tape Index (Box 24, Folder 326)
- Office of the Vice President, 1975-1977; 2; 5 Box(es)
  Subseries 2 is arranged alphabetically.
  These files were created in Washington and eventually shipped to the family archives in New York. Many of the files contain explanatory memoranda to Dr. Joseph Ernst, the family archivist.
  - Archives (Box 25, Folder 327)
    Correspondence and memoranda concerning the transfer of NAR's gubernatorial files from Albany to the Coach Barn in Pocantico Hills.
  - ARTNews - November 1975 (Box 25, Folder 328)
    Article concerning the artwork in the Vice President's Residence.
  - Attica (Box 25, Folder 329)
    Transcript of a press conference by NAR in August 1975 in which he is questioned about the Attica prison riot of September 1971.
  - Daily Correspondence Traffic Analysis, July 1975 - February 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 25, Folder 330)
  - Daringer, Helen, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 331)
    Exchange of cordial letters between NAR and Mrs. Daringer, one of his schoolteachers.
  - Directory for Mail Answering Operation (Box 25, Folder 332)
  - Directory for Mail Answering Operation (Box 25, Folder 333)
  - Domestic Council Forums Media Book (Box 25, Folder 334)
  - Domestic Council Forums Media Book (Box 25, Folder 335)
  - Domestic Council Forums Media Book (Box 25, Folder 336)
  - "The Future of Freedom" (Box 25, Folder 337)
    Printed collection of NAR speeches on issues confronting Americans in 1976.
  - Kramer, Michael and Sam Roberts (Box 25, Folder 338)
    Background file on the authors of the book, "I Never Wanted to Be Vice President of Anything."
  - Miscellaneous Files, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 0338A)
    Memo on Job-Scholarships proposal; memo re: Vice Presidential nomination from George L. Hinman in 1976; draft of an acceptance speech for President Ford; NAR notes with names of possible Vice Presidential successors; agenda for meetings with the President on July 22, 1976, including information on minority representation at Republican National Convention; status report on Job Scholarship & School Work proposals; STATUS, a monthly chartbook of Social and Economic Trends; report on New York City (7/21); memo re: black delegates from Dick Allison.
  - NAR Notes, February 1977 (Box 26, Folder 339)
  - Nursing Homes - Moreland Commission (Box 26, Folder 340)
    Material provided for the commission.
  - OEB Correspondence Operations (Box 26, Folder 341)
  - Post Vice Presidential Appointments, February - August 1977 (Box 26, Folder 342)
  - Public Forum on Domestic Policy, October 29, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 343)
    Tampa, Florida
  - "Report to the President by the Commission on CIA Activities within the United States", June 1975 (Box 26, Folder 344)
    United States Government printed report on the commission chaired by NAR.
  - Schedules, 1975-1977
    Daily schedules and itineraries for NAR.
    - Schedules, January 1975 (Box 26, Folder 345)
    - Schedules, February 1975 (Box 26, Folder 346)
    - Schedules, March 1975 (Box 26, Folder 347)
    - Schedules, April 1975 (Box 26, Folder 348)
    - Schedules, May 1975 (Box 26, Folder 349)
    - Schedules, June 1975 (Box 26, Folder 350)
    - Schedules, July 1975 (Box 26, Folder 351)
    - Schedules, August 1975 (Box 26, Folder 352)
    - Schedules, September 1975 (Box 27, Folder 353)
    - Schedules, October 1975 (Box 27, Folder 354)
    - Schedules, November 1975 (Box 27, Folder 355)
    - Schedules, December 1975 (Box 27, Folder 356)
    - Schedules, January 1976 (Box 27, Folder 357)
    - Schedules, February 1976 (Box 27, Folder 358)
    - Schedules, March 1976 (Box 27, Folder 359)
    - Schedules, April 1976 (Box 27, Folder 360)
    - Schedules, May 1976 (Box 27, Folder 361)
    - Schedules, June 1976 (Box 27, Folder 362)
    - Schedules, July 1976 (Box 27, Folder 363)
    - Schedules, August 1976 (Box 27, Folder 364)
    - Schedules, September 1976 (Box 27, Folder 365)
    - Schedules, October 1976 (Box 27, Folder 366)
    - Schedules, November 1976 (Box 27, Folder 367)
    - Schedules, January 1977 (Box 27, Folder 368)
    - Schedules, February 1977 (Box 27, Folder 369)
    - Schedules, March 1977 (Box 27, Folder 370)
    - Schedules, April 1977 (Box 27, Folder 371)
    - Schedules, May 1977 (Box 27, Folder 372)
    - Schedules, June 1977 (Box 27, Folder 373)
    - Schedules, July 1977 (Box 27, Folder 374)
    - Schedules, August 1977 (Box 27, Folder 375)
    - Schedules, September 1977 (Box 28, Folder 376)
    - Schedules, October 1977 (Box 28, Folder 377)
    - Schedules, November 1977 (Box 28, Folder 378)
    - Schedules, December 1977 (Box 28, Folder 379)
  - Stationery (Box 28, Folder 380)
    Samples of stationery used by the Vice President.
  - Stationery (Box 28, Folder 381)
  - Stationery (Box 28, Folder 382)
  - Transcripts - Interview with NAR by Professor Gellman, August 11-12, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 383)
  - Transcripts - Interview with NAR and Margaretta Fitler Rockefeller by Dan Rather for CBS News show, "Who's Who?", January 18, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 384)
  - Transcripts - Interview with NAR and Margaretta Fitler Rockefeller by Dan Rather for CBS News show, "Who's Who?", January 18, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 385)
  - Urban Development Corporation - Moreland Commission (Box 28, Folder 386)
  - Vice Presidential Seal (Box 28, Folder 387)
    Information and photographs regarding the seal, which was redesigned by NAR.
  - White House Correspondence Manual (Box 28, Folder 388)
  - White House Handbook (Box 28, Folder 389)
  - White House Pass (Box 28, Folder 390)
    Photocopy of NAR's White House pass
  - White House Press Briefings, 1976
    Copies of transcripts of briefings in which NAR was mentioned or asked about.
    - White House Press Briefings, April 5, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 391)
    - White House Press Briefings, April 6, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 392)
    - White House Press Briefings, April 12, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 393)
    - White House Press Briefings, April 22, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 394)
    - White House Press Briefings, April 26, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 395)
    - White House Press Briefings, May 13, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 396)
    - White House Press Briefings, May 17, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 397)
    - White House Press Briefings, June 1, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 398)
    - White House Press Briefings, June 10, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 399)
    - White House Press Briefings, July 20, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 400)
    - White House Press Briefings, July 22, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 401)
    - White House Press Briefings, July 29, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 402)
    - White House Press Briefings, August 2, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 403)
    - White House Press Briefings, August 3, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 404)
    - White House Press Briefings, August 11, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 405)
    - White House Press Briefings, August 23, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 406)
    - White House Press Briefings, August 31, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 407)
    - White House Press Briefings, September 7, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 408)
- Sound Recordings, 1974-1977; 3; 87 audiocassettes 23 reel-to-reel audiotapes
  Subseries 3 is grouped by format; first, audio cassettes and then reel-to-reel tapes. Each format is arranged chronologically.
  The third subseries is a collection of reel-to-reel audiotapes and audiocassettes. There are two distinct sets of audiocassettes. The first set consists of recordings of the proceedings of the confirmation hearings; the others are cassette recordings of remarks and speeches made by the Vice President. The reel-to-reel audiotapes are recordings of remarks by the Vice President and other dignitaries.
  Original tapes are restricted from scholarly research.
  Restriction-preservation concerns.
  RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
  - Senate Confirmation Hearings, September 23, 1974 - September 26, 1974; 17 cassettes (Box 1, Folder A)
    Cassette Audio Tapes
  - Senate Confirmation Hearings, November 13, 1974 - November 18, 1974; 16 cassettes (Box 1, Folder B)
  - Senate Confirmation Hearings, November 21, 1974 - November 22, 1974; 6 cassettes (Box 1, Folder C)
  - House Confirmation Hearings, November 25, 1974 - November 26, 1974; 4 cassettes (Box 2, Folder D)
  - House Confirmation Hearings, November 27, 1974; 3 cassettes (Box 2, Folder E)
  - House Confirmation Hearings, December 2, 1974; 2 cassettes (Box 2, Folder F)
  - House Confirmation Hearings, December 3, 1974 - December 5, 1974; 7 cassettes (Box 2, Folder G)
  - Dyslexia (Box 3, Folder 1.01)
  - Sam Roberts and Martin Kramer, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1.02)
  - Press Conference, Dearborn, Michigan, January 30, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.03)
  - Press Conference, Louisville, Kentucky, February 12, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.04)
  - Vice President Swearing In of Mr. Fletcher, February 25, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.05)
  - Press Conference, Chicago, Illinois, March 17, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.06)
  - Australian-American Association Dinner, March 31, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.07)
  - German Facilitative, May 10, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.08)
  - Press Conference, Frankfurt, Germany, May 15, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.09)
  - Interview with Mavuo de Medici, May 26, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.1)
  - Vaughn - Walt Bodine, August 11, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.11)
  - Interview with Professor Gellman, August 11, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.12)
  - Interview with Professor Gellman, August 12, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.13)
  - Jimmy Carter Speech at International House, August 9, 1976; Arrival, Kansas City, Missouri, August 14, 1976, August 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.14)
  - Meet the Press, August 15, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.15)
  - Nelson Gallery; New York State Delegation Caucus; New York State Reception, August 17, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.16)
  - Senator Boker Breakfast, August 17, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.17)
  - Tennessee Breakfast, August 17, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.18)
  - "Time" Editors with Jerry Udwin, August 18, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.19)
  - CBS Interview with John Hall, August 16, 1976; ABC Interview, August 18, 1976, August 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.2)
  - London, England, October 5, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.21)
  - Press Conference and DuPont Reception, Wilmington, Delaware, October 21, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.22)
  - Press Conference, NAR and Prime Minister Muldoon of New Zealand, in New Zealand, April 1 or 2, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1.23)
  - Interviews Broadcast on Radio and Television Networks of the Australian Broadcasting Company, March 15, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2.01)
  - NAR Arrival, Tours Airport, March 21, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2.02)
  - NAR Statement, Rochambeau Chateau, March 21, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2.03)
  - NAR Statement, Rochambeau Cemetery, March 21, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2.04)
  - NAR Statement, Picpus Cemetery, March 22, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2.05)
  - NAR Speech, Bicentennial Dinner, Paris, France, March 22, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2.06)
  - Press Conference, Paris, France, March 22, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2.07)
  - Press Conference, Canberra, Australia, March 30, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2.08)
  - Press Conference, Wellington, New Zealand, April 3, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2.09)
  - NAR Remarks Following Italian Earthquake, May 19, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2.1)
  - "The Mike Douglas Show", September 28, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2.11)
  - "Who's Who" with Dan Rather, January 18, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2.12)
  - England, NAR Remarks, September 15, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Reel to Reel Tapes
  - Swearing In Ceremony of Mr. Fletcher, February 25, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Tunis, Tunisia, NAR Arrival Statement, March 20, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Tunis, Tunisia, NAR Departure Statement, March 21, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Tunisia and France, NAR Remarks, March 20, 1976 - March 22, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Paris, France, Bicentennial Speech, March 22, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - France, NAR Remarks, March 22, 1976 - March 23, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Malaysia, Singapore, and Australia, NAR Remarks, March 27, 1976 - March 28, 1976, March 31, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Kuala Lumpur Malaysia NAR Remarks, March 27, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Singapore, NAR Speech, March 28, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Sydney, Australia, Speech by Australian Prime Minister Malcom Fraser, March 29, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Australia, NAR Remarks, March 30, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Canberra, Australia, NAR Press Conference, March 30, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Wentworth Hotel, NAR Speech, March 31, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - New Zealand, NAR Remarks, April 2, 1976 - April 3, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - The Commonwealth Club, NAR Speech, May 4, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - The Biltmore Hotel, NAR Speech to the World Affairs Council Luncheon, May 5, 1976; 1 of 2 tapes (Box 12, Folder 0017A)
  - The Biltmore Hotel, NAR Speech to the World Affairs Council Luncheon, May 5, 1976; 2 of 2 tapes (Box 12, Folder 0017B)
  - Representative Conable, Remarks, May 23, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - NAR Address, at the Graduation Ceremonies of the United States Air Force Academy, June 2, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - NAR Address, to the Inter-American Defense College, June 10, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Dedication of Old Senate Chamber (NAR involved), June 16, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Unknown Contents, June 29, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Unknown Contents, n. d. (Box 15, Folder 23)